<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title><![CDATA[PHP-ES]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/tags/php.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://www.phpes.org/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-03T20:02:37-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.phpes.org/</id>
        <generator uri="http://sculpin.io/">Sculpin</generator>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[NFePHP]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/05/03/nfephp"/>
            <updated>2016-05-03T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/05/03/nfephp</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>API para comunicação entre o emitente de NFe e os serviços dos SEFAZ estaduais. Inteiramente construído em PHP, roda em qualquer sistema operacional.
  NFePHP é uma API para gerenciamento das comunicações entre o emitente de NFe e os serviços dos SEFAZ estaduais. Inteiramente construído em PHP para rodar sob qualquer sistema operacional.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Fonte: <a href="https://github.com/nfephp-org/nfephp">https://github.com/nfephp-org/nfephp</a></p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Piwik]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/05/02/piwik"/>
            <updated>2016-05-02T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/05/02/piwik</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://piwik.org/">Piwik</a> é uma alternativa opensource ao Google Analytics, escrito em PHP e que utiliza MySQL como base de dados.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Piwik is a full featured PHP MySQL software program that you download and install on your own webserver. At the end of the five minute installation process you will be given a JavaScript code. Simply copy and paste this tag on websites you wish to track and access your analytics reports in real time.</p>
  
  <p>Piwik aims to be a Free software alternative to Google Analytics, and is already used on more than 1,000,000 websites. Privacy is built-in!</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Symfony]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/29/awesome-symfony"/>
            <updated>2016-04-29T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/29/awesome-symfony</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Coletânea com bundles, utilitários e recursos para desenvolvimento utilizando o framework Symfony.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A list of awesome Symfony bundles, utilities and resources.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Fonte: <a href="https://github.com/sitepoint/awesome-symfony">https://github.com/sitepoint/awesome-symfony</a></p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jobby]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/28/jobby"/>
            <updated>2016-04-28T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/28/jobby</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Com <a href="https://github.com/jobbyphp/jobby">Jobby</a> você gerencia os jobs através do PHP sem necessidade de alterar a crontab.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Install the master jobby cron job, and it will manage all your offline tasks. Add jobs without modifying crontab. Jobby can handle logging, locking, error emails and more.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Basta apenas uma entrada principal na crontab.</p>

<pre><code>* * * * * cd /path/to/project &amp;&amp; php jobby.php 1&gt;&gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1
</code></pre>

<p>Funcionalidades:</p>

<ul>
<li>Maintain one master crontab job.</li>
<li>Jobs run via PHP, so you can run them under any programmatic conditions.</li>
<li>Use ordinary crontab schedule syntax (powered by the excellent cron-expression).</li>
<li>Run only one copy of a job at a given time.</li>
<li>Send email whenever a job exits with an error status.</li>
<li>Run job as another user, if crontab user has sudo privileges.</li>
<li>Run only on certain hostnames (handy in webfarms).</li>
<li>Theoretical Windows support (but not ever tested)</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pagekit CMS]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/26/pagekit-cms"/>
            <updated>2016-04-26T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/26/pagekit-cms</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Divulgado hoje no blog do Symfony o novo CMS <a href="https://pagekit.com/">PageKit</a>, que tem o código-fonte aberto e é construído utilizando os components do Symfony. Segundo definição do site do projeto, o PageKit é um CMS moderno, intuitivo, modular, e flexível.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Pagekit is an Open Source CMS built with several Symfony Components. Recently we had the opportunity to meet with Jan Schönherr, one of its lead developers, and we talked with him about Symfony and Pagekit.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Fonte: <a href="http://symfony.com/blog/pagekit-an-open-source-cms-built-with-symfony-components">http://symfony.com/blog/pagekit-an-open-source-cms-built-with-symfony-components</a></p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[PuPHPet]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/25/puphpet"/>
            <updated>2016-04-25T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/25/puphpet</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://puphpet.com/">Puphpet</a> é uma ferramenta gráfica para gerar configuração de máquinas virtuais para o desenvolvimento web. Suporta Vagrant e Puppet.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A simple GUI to set up virtual machines for Web development.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Como usar o MongoDB com PHP]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/20/como-usar-o-mongodb-com-php"/>
            <updated>2016-04-20T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/20/como-usar-o-mongodb-com-php</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Dentre os bancos de dados NoSQL da atualidade um dos mais usados é o MongoDB, seja pela sua eficiência em trabalhar com enormes volumes de dados ou pela sua flexibilidade, algo comum em bancos NoSQL. Abordaremos neste artigo como trabalhar com ele no PHP.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Fonte: <a href="https://blog.butecopensource.org/como-usar-o-mongodb-com-php/">https://blog.butecopensource.org/como-usar-o-mongodb-com-php/</a></p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[PPM - PHP Process Manager]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/19/ppm-php-process-manager"/>
            <updated>2016-04-19T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/19/ppm-php-process-manager</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PHP-PM é um gerenciador de processo, supercharger e load balancer para aplicações PHP que chega a ser 15 vezes mais rápidos do uma aplicação PHP tradicional.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It's based on ReactPHP and works best with applications that use request-response frameworks like Symfony's HTTPKernel. The approach of this is to kill the expensive bootstrap of PHP (declaring symbols, loading/parsing files) and the bootstrap of feature-rich frameworks. See Performance section for a quick hint. PHP-PM basically spawns several PHP instances as worker bootstraping your application (eg. the whole Symfony Kernel) and hold it in the memory to be prepared for every incoming request: This is why PHP-PM makes your application so fast.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Repositório do projeto: <a href="https://github.com/php-pm/php-pm">https://github.com/php-pm/php-pm</a></p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aplicação Symfony como HTTP Server]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/18/aplicacao-symfony-como-http-server"/>
            <updated>2016-04-18T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/18/aplicacao-symfony-como-http-server</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tutorial ensinando transformar uma aplicação Symfony em um servidor HTTP pronto para executar, e sem necessidade servidor adicional como por exemplo NGINX e/ou Apache2, utilizando a biblioteca ReactPHP.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>TL;DR: Run your application as a HTTP server to increase its performances.</p>
  
  <p>HTTP frameworks, such as Symfony, allow us to build applications that have the potential to achieve Super Speed.</p>
  
  <p>A first way to make use of it is to run our application as a HTTP server. In this article we'll take a Symfony application and demonstrate how to run it as HTTP server using ReactPHP.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Fonte: <a href="https://gnugat.github.io/2016/04/13/super-speed-sf-react-php.html">https://gnugat.github.io/2016/04/13/super-speed-sf-react-php.html</a></p>
]]></content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHP must watch]]></title>
            <link href="http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/14/php-must-watch"/>
            <updated>2016-04-14T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
            <id>http://www.phpes.org/blog/2016/04/14/php-must-watch</id>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/phptodayorg/php-must-watch">PHP must watch</a> é um repositório contendo uma lista de conferências sobre PHP:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A list of interesting conference talks and great videos on PHP. Inspired by js-must-watch</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </entry>
    </feed>